Kenneth David Swegman Jr.

997 Cumberland Road, Pittsburgh, PA 15237 • (412)-499-4148 • kenneth.swegman@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Recently graduated Computer Scientist with a background in Computer Security and DevOps. Experience with both low-level and high-level languages such as C, and JavaScript. I bring a hard-working attitude, with an ever-growing curiosity of new technologies and techniques. Currently working towards Security+ Certification.

EDUCATION

LA ROCHE UNIVERSITY, Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (CS), August 2020

TECHNICAL SKILL

Languages	C C# Python JavaScript SQL
Methodologies	Agile Development
Technologies	PowerShell SQL Server Azure Logic Apps ARM Templates Docker Kali Linux Splunk Bash JSON XML ASP.NET MVC 5 T-SQL Entity Framework 6 jQuery HTML/CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INFOSHAPE SOFTWARE LLC, Pittsburgh, PA

Software Developer I, Dec 2020 – Apr 2021

- Created web pages using the ASP.NET MVC 5 framework.
- Worked as a full-stack developer. Utilized T-SQL Stored Procedures, and on the code side, used Entity Framework 6 to work with database.
- Used JavaScript and jQuery to work on Views.

DUQUESNE LIGHT CO., Pittsburgh, PA

DevOps Engineering Intern, May 2019 – Dec 2019

- Created automated workflow to funnel weather tracking data into a financial analytics system using Azure Logic Apps
- Developed weather system using Power-BI for the frontend and Azure Infrastructure on the backend
- Set up multiple servers, databases, and virtual machines for other projects within the company
- Developed script to automate creation of virtual machines and other resources in Azure using Powershell
- Executed testing and developed scripts with QA Testing team for new Integration Platform rollout

IT Intern, May 2017 – Aug 2017

- Shadowed ReactJS Developers, and .NET Framework Developers
- Learned fundamentals of Web Development (HTML/CSS/JS)

ACTIVITIES/ACHIEVEMENTS

- Competed in Steel Hacks 2018 and built Mozilla Firefox Plugin
- Radio Club President 2018-2019
- Film Club Vice President 2018-2019
- AITP Member 2015-2019